## **EVANS IJEOMA PAUL**

Paulijeoma39@gmail.com +44 7459585472 96 Langworthy Road Manchester M40 5EQ

## **Summary:**

An experienced and driven security expert with 7+ years' experience protecting people, resources, properties and data for various companies and businesses. demonstrated proficiency in evaluating risk, modifying threats, and creating emergency response plans. Skilled in establishing and managing security practices, conducting thorough investigations, and working with diverse teams to ensure complete security measures. Seeking to apply a track record of improving security operations to contribute to the protection and well-being of a reputable organization.

#### **SKILLS:**

- Crisis intervention
- Ethics and professionalism
- Safety Compliance
- Security risk management
- Security awareness
- Digital security application
- Interrogation and statement

### WORK EXPERIENCE

January 2023 –December 2023

# **Security Officer Event Coordinator - (Moirah Event Solutions) Huddersfield England**

## **Responsibilities:**

- Ensure the safety of attendees and staff while protecting the venue and property.
- Duties includes using customer service skills to deal with the general public .
- Searching the ar ea before and after the Guest vacate the premises
- Communicating with the team to ensure the safety of People within the premises and the avenue runs smoothly.

January 2021 –December 2022

## **Security Officer: Muscat Mall Oman**

- Carrying out security checks on visitors, on arrival and exit using security scanners and other equipment.
- Performing luggage checks as required.
- Keeping a record of all visitors, including the time of arrival and departure.
- Monitoring surveillance cameras.
- Responding to alarms within the premises.

- Patrolling the premises regularly to ensure nothing is out of place.
- Liaising with law enforcement in the case of suspected or reported criminal activity.
- Performing scheduled and random checks of designated areas throughout the facility to check for any security breaches.
- Assisting the maintenance staff in securing an area during a maintenance emergency.

#### October 2018 - December 2020

## Security Guard: District 45 Club, Nigeria

- Carrying out security checks on visitors, on arrival using security scanners and other equipment.
- Performing luggage checks as required.
- Patrolling the premises regularly to ensure nothing is out of place.
- Liaising with law enforcement in the case of suspected or reported criminal activity.

## May 2014 – September 2018

## Security Guard: Golden Cocktail Hotel, Nigeria

- Carrying out security checks on visitors, on arrival and exit using security scanners and other equipment.
- Performing luggage checks as required.
- Keeping a record of all visitors, including the time of arrival and departure.
- Patrolling the premises regularly to ensure nothing is out of place.
- Liaising with law enforcement in the case of suspected or reported criminal activity.

## **EDUCATION**

Oct. 2010 – Nov. 2012 AUCHI POLYTECHNIC, AUCHI Higher National Diploma (**Statistics**)

Sept. 2007– Oct. 2009 AUCHI POLYTECHNIC, AUCHI National Diploma (**Statistics**)

Sept. 2000 – Jun. 2006 Ugo College Secondary School, Edo State Nigeria West Africa Senior School Certificate

#### References

Available on request